NAMAN KHURPIA

Spring Boot | Angular | React Graphic Designer (PS | Ai | XD) Android Developer | NodeJS



ABOUT ME

Email

namankhurpia2@gmail.com

Phone

+919039658263

Web

<u>namank.xyz</u>

Blog blog.namank.xyz

HOBBIES







Creating Music



Designing







SKILLS

Android | Angular | Spring | Django Java | Junit | Machine Learning Spring Microservices & load Balancing | XML | Android Gradle | Android Maven | Firebase | Crash Analytics | MVC | GIT | AR | Unity | Prototyping | Unity | Vuforia Experience Design | Photoshop | Eureka Naming Server | Ribbon HTML | CSS | JS |

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

Course	Univeristy/School	Score	Year
Secondary	Sagar Public School (CBSE)	8.4 CGPA	2014
Higher Secondary	Sagar Public School (CBSE)	88%	2016
B Tech, CSE	Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore	8.49 CGPA	2020

Possessing good knowledge of Java (JSE + JEE) including Data Structures, Expertise on Spring Boot, Angular 9, Android App Development. Spring Security, Netflix OSS, Client-side load balancing (Ribbon), Dynamic scaling (Eureka Naming Server), Ribbon, API Gateway (Zuul), Deployment on AWS, Authentication O-Auth2, Dependency Injection, JDBC via MySQL and H2.

Android Application Development (uploaded 3 apps/games on Playstore),

Ability to Design Minimalistic UI for Android, iOS and Web Apps, Prototype UI and add animations, Optimizing Android apps.

Machine Learning & Deep Learning enthusiast,

Making AR apps in Unity.

Kindly visit **namank.xyz** for more.

WORK EXPERIENCE

TCS Digital - Systems Engineer

Cloud, Microservices & APIfication) (Aug 2020 - Present)

TCS Digital - 4 months

Cloud, Microservices & APIfication) Intern (Jan 2020 - May 2020)

PROJECTS

- 1. Western Union Money Transfer Utility A platform build on Spring Boot & Angular that allows a large enterprise to send money internationally, having simultaneous currency updates and multiple types of money transfer.
- 2. Paper VIT (2019) Question paper viewing app (Android) for VIT University, implemented Facebook ads for monetisation of service, view here
- 3. Easy Ed (beta) (2018) An Android-based application which enables visualizing various scientific concepts in 3-D using augmented reality.

and many more. Check Github

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 1. Special Achievement Award by TCS (2021) Employee of the week during award Sprint.
- 2. Lead Author for publishing research paper in Springer Journal (2021) **Topic** - Molecular Dynamics using Open MP + OpenMP SIMD, Optimized Verlet's algorithm that allows computation of molecular forces.
- 3. Lead Android Developer & Events Head at Apple Developers Group (2018-2019), a VIT Chapter certified by Apple Developers University Program
- 4. 3rd Prize Winner at Hack4Cause (2018) A Hackathon in the field of Digital Image Processing via Augmented reality organised by IEEE-SSIT.
- 5. 1st Prize at MLH Local-Hackday (2018) An open Hackathon organized by DSC - GitHub, developed a human sentiment analysis using classification